[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Other examples of document retrieval.
文章检索的其他例子
Okay?
明白?
So we're gonna go through a few.
所以我们会展示一些其他的例子
For example, let's take the singer Taylor Swift.
比如说 让我们用歌手Taylor Swift (泰勒·斯威夫特) 作为例子
So out of all my people,
所以在我们表中的所有人当中
I'm going to select the one
我会选出一位
whose name is Taylor Swift.
她的名字是Taylor Swift (泰勒·斯威夫特)
And so when I select her I can ask,
并且当我选中她的时候我可以问
let's retrieve some documents that are similar to Taylor Swift's documents.
让我们检索一些和Taylor Swift (泰勒·斯威夫特) 的词条最相似的词条
In other words, who are the people, just for
换句话说 哪些人
the model, who are the people who are closest to Taylor Swift?
仅仅对于这个模型来说 哪些人和Taylor Swift (泰勒·斯威夫特) 距离最近
So she's a female singer and you'll see other female
她是一个女歌手 所以你会看到其他女性
singers kind of the same generation like Carrie Underwood,
歌手和她同时代的 比如Carrie Underwood (凯莉·安德伍德)
Alicia Keys, Jordan Sparks, Leona Lewis.
Alicia Keys (艾丽西亚·凯斯) Jordan Sparks (乔丁·斯帕克斯) Leona Lewis (丽安娜·刘易斯)
And just a little disclaimer here, I had to go and
在这里作个小小的声明 我得去
look those people up in Wikipedia because I really didn't know who they were.
维基百科上查找这些人才行 因为我真的不认识她们是谁
[LAUGH] Here we go.
让我们继续
Let's take another example.
让我们再看另一个例子
So for example, the actress Angelina Jolie.
比如说 女演员 Angelina Jolie (安吉丽娜·朱莉)
So if I take, out of all my people,
所以如果在表里所有的人当中选出她
I take the one whose name is Angelina Jolie.
选出名字叫做Angelina Jolie (安吉丽娜·朱莉) 的人物
And I'm now going to query my nearest neighbor
然后我会查询我的最近邻居模型
model to ask who is closest to Angelina Jolie.
去询问谁是最接近Angelina Jolie (安吉丽娜·朱莉) 的人
And so who is closer to Angelina Jolie?
所以到底谁离 Angelina Jolie (安吉丽娜·朱莉) 更近呢？
Before I press enter here, take a moment to think.
在我按下回车之前 让我们花一点时间想想
If you know anything about this actress Angelina Jolie,
如果你了解过任何关于 Angelina Jolie (安吉丽娜·朱莉) 这个女演员的事
you might guess who is the closest person to her, and
你可能就会猜测谁是离她最近的人
if I run this, you'll see that the nearest neighbor is Brad Pitt.
如果我运行这个函数 你会看到最近的邻居是Brad Pitt (布拉德·皮特)
And we all know about the relationship between Angelina Jolie and Brad Pitt.
并且我们都知道Angelina Jolie (安吉丽娜·朱莉) 和 Brad Pitt (布拉德·皮特) 之间的关系
And then you see Julianne Moore, Billy Bob Thornton, George Clooney, these are all
然后你还会看到Julianne Moore (朱丽安·摩尔) Bill Bob Thornton (比利·鲍伯·松顿) George Clooney (乔治·克鲁尼)这些都是
actors and actresses that have been in movies actually with Angelina Jolie.
在电影中和Angelina Jolie (安吉丽娜·朱莉) 一起合演过 的男演员和女演员
So, It's pretty cool.
所以这很酷吧
We get some interesting retrieval here.
我们得到了一些有趣的检索
So let me show you one last cool, fun example.
让我给你们展示最后一个酷和有趣的例子
So you might be familiar with a person called
你可能对一个人很熟悉 他名叫
Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Arnold Schwarzenegger (阿诺德·施瓦辛格)
The famous Terminator.
有名的终结者
So, I actually have to cheat here to
事实上在这里我需要作弊一下
make sure I get his last name right,
确保我正确拼写出了他的名字
Schwarzenegger, okay.
Schwarzenegger 好的
Hopefully I got that right.
希望我写的是对的
And the question is, who are the nearest neighbors to Arnold Schwarzenegger?
问题来了 谁是Arnold Schwarzenegger (阿诺德·施瓦辛格) 最近的邻居呢？
Now.
现在
You may know that Arnold had a double career.
你可能知道Arnold有双重的生涯
So first, he start as an actor, well,
首先他从一个演员开始 好的
bodybuilder, then an actor, then a politician, and became
准确来说是从健美运动员开始 然后是演员 接着是政治家 然后成为了
the governor of the state of California in the United States, so several lives.
美国加利福尼亚州的州长 所以有多重生涯
So what are the nearest neighbors for Arnold Schwarzenegger?
所以谁是Arnold Schwarzenegger (阿诺德·施瓦辛格) 最近的邻居呢？
And so you'll see Arnold Schwarzenegger.
你会首先看到Arnold Schwarzenegger (阿诺德·施瓦辛格) 自己
Then you'll see Jessie Ventura, who is like a,
接着你会看到 Jessie Ventura (杰西·文图拉)
Jessie Venture is a wrestler, an actor, so similar to Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Jessie Ventura (杰西·文图拉) 是一个摔跤运动员 也是一个演员 所以和Arnold Schwarzenegger (阿诺德·施瓦辛格) 很像
And then a few politicians, including former
接着会看到一些政治家 包括前任
governors of Oregon, and of Rhode Island and other states in the United States.
俄勒冈州长 罗德岛州长 以及美国一些其他州的州长
So now we see that the nearest neighbors for Arnold are politicians and
现在我们可以看到 Arnold的最近邻居是 政治家和
actors and body builders, people like him.
演员以及健美运动员 这些和他相似的人物
So this was a really cool example of just building a very simple document retrieval
所以这真的是一个很酷的例子 对于仅仅是构建一个非常简单的词条检索
system using TFIDF and nearest neighbors.
系统并使用TFIDF和最近邻居模型来说
Just like we learned in the module, but now taking it to practice and
就像我们在之前模块的教学单元中学到的一样 但我们把它们运用到了实际中 并且
finding some pretty cool documents from this Wikipedia data set.
从维基百科的数据集中检索到了一些很酷的词条
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community